AJU GEORGE JACOB

ASPIRING SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Home: 011-40452880 Mobile: +91-9990639600 ajugjacob@computer.org

Delhi. Kerala

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a 22-year-old Computer Science major who has a strong foundation in software engineering and programming principles over multiple platforms. Quick learner and master new technologies; successful working in both team and self directed environments

SPECIALIZATIONS

- Python
- Go Language
- C & C++
- MERN Stack
- MySQL / NoSQL
- API
- Swagger
- Docker
- Apache Druid
- RabbitMQ

ACHIEVEMENTS

Shortlisted for CoronaSafe Engineering Fellowship

Was shortlisted among the top 50 from over 45,000+ applications for CoronaSafe Engineering Fellowship which was backed by All India Council of Technical Education (AICTE).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern

Founding Minds Inc. | July 2021 - October 2021

- Assigned to Banking and Finance Division and worked with one of the most exciting new startups based in California
- Worked in creating a microservice application using Golang and Python as well as developed a model for algorithmic underwriting while using RabbitMQ as a broker
- Created RESTful APIs according to OAS specifications also created a Swagger API Documentation for the same
- Also integrated the data with Apache Druid from S3

.NET Developer Intern

Clowderin | 2018 - 2019

- Worked with the team to develop the enterprises product
- Took a session on basic web development for 150+ students as part of an outreach program

EDUCATION HIGHLIGHTS

College of Engineering, Chengannur

BTech Computer Science & Engineering | 2018 - 2022

- CS Chair, IEEE SB CEC
- Mentor, CS DevCom
- CGPA 8.4

Faith Academy Sr. Sec. School

Student | 2015 - 2018

- School House Captain
- Class X CGPA 9.2
- Class XII Percentage 89.8

LEADERSHIP

CS Chair, IEEE SB CEC

- Organized over 25 events, workshops and competitions for student members.
- Multiple events including Learn to Code (an initiative to encourage girls to code), ISQIP 20, Machine Learning track (lead student mentor).

EC Coordinator, IEEE SB CEC

- Design Lead for all the events/ workshops conducted by IEEE SB College of Engineering Chengannur.
- Lead Student Volunteer in SB Program by IEEE R10 (Asia-Pacific) SYWL Congress which included many internationally well-known speakers and innovators.